Guide to the Asian CineVision Records TAM.416
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Video Recordings, 545120
  - Video 273: CCTV, March 22, 1981; Cuid6207 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid6207)
    This episode includes three parts: a report on a protest, news coverage, and a 26-minute film. The first part covers a boycott campaign against the launch of the film Charlie Chan: The Curse of Dragon Queen. Street interviews with people about their opinion on the film and on the boycott are included. The second part is CCTV news report which covers international, national and local news. Local news covered includes a subway workers' strike in New York City, and the New York Police Department's massive search for and arrest of a suspect allegedly involved in murdering three CBS employees. Interviews with two New York policemen are included. The third part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 59 minutes
  - Video 274: CCTV, May 1981; Cuid9316 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9316)
    This episode features three documentaries. The first is WFAA Production's Welcome to America about Vienamese refugees' life in the United States, directed by Jerry Cadigan and first aired on October 10, 1979. The second is a WNET/Thirteen documentary called New Immigrants, documenting the struggles and anxieties of Korean immigrants in New York City. The third is a 5-minute excerpt from the 1979 Academy Award-winning film From Mao to Mozart: Isaac Stern in China, directed by Allan Miller.
  - Video 275: CCTV, July 14, 1981; Cuid9317 (Box 96, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid9317)
    This episode includes five parts: news reports, a report on a social service club, a report on a film festival, an excerpt of a Hong Kong film, and segments of a puppet show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The second part covers the inauguration ceremony of the 1981-82 leadership of Lions Club Chinatown. The third part features highlights of the 1971 Asian American Film Festival. The fourth part of the episode showcases an excerpt of Hong Kong film Dangerous Encounter - 1st Kind () (1980), directed by Tsui Hark (). The last section features Chinese traditional puppet shows performed by the Quanzhou puppet troupe originated from Fujian Province, People's Republic of China.
  - Video 276: CCTV, July 19, 1981; Cuid15041 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15041)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a feature. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week, highlighting the Chinatown Summer Cultural Festival. The second part features a boycott campaign against the launch of film Charlie Chan: The Curse of Dragon Queen Also included are street interviews with people about their opinion on the film and on the boycott.
  - Video 277: CCTV, July 26, 1981; Cuid15042 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15042)
    This episode includes four parts: news reports, an interview with a Hong Kong celebrity, a protest, and a segment of a Chinese animation film. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes a protest by African Americans who demand job opportunities. The protest is held at a construction site on Madison Avenue in New York City. The second part is an interview with Doris Law () who is a former Miss Hong Kong Pageant recipient. The third part covers a rally at Lincoln Center in New York City, protesting against budget cuts for the arts. Interviews with participating artists are included. The last part of the program shows a segment of a Chinese animated film Prince Nezha's Triumph Against Dragon King () (1979).
  - Video 278: CCTV, August 2, 1981; Cuid15043 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15043)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports, and an interview with a Hong Kong film director. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week including the 1980 United States census results on the population of Chinese Americans. The population numbers were more than 800,000, which exceeded the population of other Asian ethnicities. The second part features an interview with Hong Kong film director Tsui Hark (). Clips from Tsui Hark's films are also included.
  - Video 279: CCTV, August 9, 1981; Cuid15044 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15044)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a feature on a Chinese performance troupe, and coverage of a cultural festival. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The second part features Shanghai Peking Opera troupe's visit to New York; performances and interviews are included. The third part highlights the Third Asian/Pacific American Heritage Festival, which was held in Lincoln Center on May 2, 1981.
  - Video 280: CCTV, August 16, 1081; Cuid15045 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15045)
    This episode includes two parts: a news report, and a 26-minute Hong Kong film. The first part includes extensive coverage of international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In the local news section, the host announces the changes and current status of Chinese American population in the country. The announcement is based on the 1980 United States census. The second part is an Allen Fong () film Song of Yuen Chau Chai () (1977), which depicts the lives of fishermen in Hong Kong.
  - Video 281: CCTV, August 23, 1981; Cuid15046 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15046)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, the Beautifying Chinatown () project is covered. Street interviews in Chinatown are included. The local news also features an anti-eviction movement in Chinatown. Interviews with organizers from Asian Americans For Equality and building management personnel are included. Highlights from Shanghai Peking Opera troupe's performance in New York City are also showcased.
  - Video 282: CCTV, August 30, 1981; Cuid15047 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15047)
    This episode includes news reports that extensively cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. Local news features a unionization movement organized by Chinese restaurant workers in midtown New York City. Local news also includes an award presentation ceremony organized by International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU) which presents scholarships to children of Chinese American union members. At last, a martial art contest is featured.
  - Video 283: CCTV, September 6, 1981; Cuid15048 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15048)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes the New York City mayoral election campaigns in Chinatown. Interviews with two candidates, Frank Barbaro and Ed Koch, are included. This episode also includes interviews with Chinese Americans who will run for district representatives as Democrats. The last section of the episode includes street interviews with people about their views on roller skating.
  - Video 284: CCTV, September 13, 1981; Cuid15049 (Box 97, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15049)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news features, the Labor Day parade in New York City, which celebrates the hundred-year anniversary of the establishment of labor unionization is highlighted. The episode also features the opening ceremony of the Products Exhibition of Jiangsu Province organized at Sino-American Commodities Center.
  - Video 285: CCTV, September 20, 1981; Cuid15050 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15050)
    This episode includes news reports that cover international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, the Labor Day parade in New York City celebrating the hundred-year anniversary of the establishment of labor unionization is covered. For the first time, Chinese American labor unions join the parade. Interviews with union leaders and members are included. News about the Peng Teng Restaurant labor strike is covered. The episode also features the opening ceremony of the Products Exhibition of Jiangsu Province organized at Sino-American Commodities Center.
  - Video 286: CCTV, October 4, 1981; Cuid15051 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15051)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a current affairs forum. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes an interview with a Chinatown tenant who suffers from shortage of hot water and heating. Highlights from the Asian American Festival are also included. The second part is a current affairs forum called Fact? Debate? (??). In this episode, a campaign opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. The representative from Community Board No. 3 (Manhattan), Virginia M. Kee, and the representative from Asian Americans For Equality, Doris Koo, express their opinions.
  - Video 287: CCTV, October 11, 1981; Cuid15052 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15052)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a social service program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news features a campaign that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. Chinatown residents and Asian Americans For Equality demand a public hearing in the Chinatown community. The episode also includes a feature report introducing the history of services provided by the New York Public Library Chinatown branch located at 33 East Broadway, New York City. The second part is a program called At Your Service () in which the Chinatown Daycare Center is featured. The Chinatown Daycare Center, founded in 1969, faces financial burden and will be demolished by the state government.
  - Video 288: CCTV, October 18, 1981; Cuid15053 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15053)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a travel program, and a Chinese puppet show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. A history of early Chinese immigrants in the United States is featured. The second part is a program called Travelogue () in which Orchard Crest farm in New Jersey is introduced. The third part features Chinese traditional puppet shows performed by the Quanzhou puppet troupe which originated in Fujian Province, People's Republic of China.
  - Video 289: CCTV, October 25, 1981; Cuid15054 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15054)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a dance show, and a travel program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. Local news includes coverage of a campaign that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. Interviews with Chinatown residents being evicted are included. The episode also introduces the first generation Chinese typing computer. The second part shows performance highlights from the Chinese Dance Company of N.Y. Performances include Chinese folk dance, classic dance and martial art dance. The third part is a program called Travelogue (), which covers Sheepshead Bay in New York City, New York state.
  - Video 290: CCTV, November 1, 1981; Cuid15055 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15055)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a cultural show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. Local news includes coverage of a campaign that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. Also included in this episode is a segment on a public hearing held by Community Board No. 3 (Manhattan) to discuss the Special Manhattan Bridge District with Chinatown residents. Opinions by politicians, Chinatown residents and activists are expressed. The second part shows performances from the Chinatown Summer Cultural Festival.
  - Video 291: CCTV, November 8, 1981; Cuid15056 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15056)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a feature on a choir, and the arrival of a Chinese opera troupe. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, debts carried by the Chinatown Daycare Center are taken over by the Chinese Consolidated Benevolent Association. The second part features performances by a Chinese choir in New York City. The third part features Shanghai Peking Opera troupe's visit to New York.
  - Video 292: CCTV, November 14, 1981; Cuid15057 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15057)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a feature report on a university information event, and a social service program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, a Chinatown physician and nurse are interviewed on how to cope with disease in the winter season; the shortage of healthcare among Chinese community is mentioned. The second part features a university information session called College Day organized by the East Coast Asian Student Union. Student representatives from different universities are interviewed. The third part is Hello Mother (), in which the hosts interview Ms. Kwan about cosmetic and makeup skills. After the interview, Ms. Kwan holds a makeup demonstration.
  - Video 293: CCTV, November 22, 1981; Cuid15058 (Box 98, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15058)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, an interview with a Chinese artist, and an interview with a martial arts master. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, a new drama is presented by the Pan Asian Repertory. The second part features an interview with Chinese sculptor Situ Jie (). The third part includes an interview with a martial arts master and his students. A demonstration of Chinese traditional lion dancing performance is also included.
  - Video 294: CCTV, November 29, 1981; Cuid15059 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15059)
    This video includes four parts: news reports, a feature on a Chinese painter, a television drama, and an interview. First, the news bulletin includes extensive coverage of international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, the testimony Japanese Americans recounting being evacuated and mistreated by the U.S. government during World War II. The local news also includes the graduation dinner of CCTV's sixth session of the Production and Performance Workshop. The second part is a feature on Chinese painter Zhu Shengguang (). The third part is a television drama production called Nightmare, a collective production by students from CCTV's Production and Performance workshop. The fourth part features a martial arts master who specializes in Wing Chun.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 61 minutes.
  - Video 295: CCTV, December 13, 1981; Cuid15060 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15060)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a travel program, and a social service program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The second part is a program called Travelogue () that highlights Walt Disney World theme park in Orlando, Florida, United States. The third part is a social service program called Portrait () which in this episode discusses neurasthenia. Street interviews with Chinatown residents and an interview with a Chinese physician about neurasthenia are included.
  - Video 296: CCTV, December 5, 1981; Cuid15061 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15061)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and highlights of a cultural program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, a protest is organized by Asian Americans For Equality. The protest demands that the city redesign the Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project to benefit small business owners and local residents. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. The local news also includes interviews with Chinese teenage athletes who visit New York City to attend a competition organized by the United States Association of Independent Gymnastics Club (USAIGC). The second part features a performance by a Chinese choir in New York City.
  - Video 297: CCTV, December 20, 1981; Cuid15062 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15062)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports, and a travel program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes a report on the success of the New York City janitors' strike whose demands for an increase of salary and insurance subsidy were met. The local news also includes an interview with Hong Kong singer Roman Tam () who performs in Atlantic City, New Jersey. The second part is a program called Travelogue () and covers the Walt Disney World theme park in Orlando, Florida, United States.
  - Video 298: CCTV, December 27, 1981; Cuid15063 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15063)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports, and a cultural program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes coverage of Christmas activities in New York City and a celebration of Christmas in Chinatown. Also included are highlights of an orchestra performance. The second part features a performance by Hong Kong singer Roman Tam () who holds solo concerts in Atlantic City, New Jersey.
  - Video 299: CCTV, January 3, 1982; Cuid15064 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15064)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports, and a television drama show. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The beginning of the episode highlights the annual count-down to the New Year in Times Square, New York City. The local news covers the opposition to the Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project organized by Asian American for Equality. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. The second part of the episode shows a CCTV television drama production Dream of Gold Mountain ().
  - Video 300: CCTV, January 11, 1982; Cuid15065 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15065)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, street interviews, and a feature program about Chinatown talents. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. In local news, Chinatown residents and non-government organizations sue the New York City Mayor's Office of Management and Budget, New York Department of Housing and Urban Development, and a Chinese American developer on the issue of launching the Special Manhattan Bridge District project without sufficient public consultation. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing old buildings. This section also covers news about the Chinese American Planning Council, which obtained federal funds to build apartment buildings for seniors and people with disabilities. The second part includes street interviews with Chinatown residents on the topic of coping with cold weather. The third part is a feature on the first woman taxi driver from Chinatown.
  - Video 301: CCTV, January 17, 1982; Cuid15066 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15066)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, and two cultural programs. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes street interviews with Chinatown residents about the extremely cold weather they are enduring. Also in local news, a community forum is organized by a group that opposes the Special Manhattan Bridge District project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing older buildings. The second part is a feature report on a martial arts school in Chinatown. The third part highlights Hong Kong photographer Anita Au who discusses her photographs that document 1980s city life in the People's Republic of China.
  - Video 302: CCTV, January 24, 1982; Cuid15067 (Box 99, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15067)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a cultural program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes an extensive interview with Counselor Joyce Moy who represents Chinatown residents and other non-governmental organizations in a legal pursuit against the New York City Mayor's Office of Management and Budget, the New York Department of Housing and Urban Development, and a Chinese American developer on the issue of Special Manhattan Bridge District rezoning project. The project intends to renew the neighborhood by demolishing older buildings. The local news also covers a forum organized by the Asian Americans for Equality on the issue of rental increase in Chinatown. The second part features traditional Chinese cultural activities.
    Format: 3/4" Umatic, Duration: 58 minutes, 46 seconds
  - Video 303: CCTV, January 31, 1982; Cuid15068 (Box 100, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15068)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a cultural program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news features Chinatown residents celebrating Lunar New Year, the Year of the Dog in the Chinese zodiac calendar. The news also features an Asian American literature club gathering at the Bayard Street Cafe. The second part features a performance by Hong Kong singer Alan Tam () who holds solo concerts in Atlantic City, New Jersey. Tam and his girlfriend are interviewed by the host.
  - Video 304: CCTV, February 7, 1982; Cuid15069 (Box 100, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15069)
    This episode includes two parts: news reports and a cultural program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The local news includes an eviction case in Chinatown. The landlord of the building at 109 Madison Street Manhattan is Thomas Sun (). Also covered, the launch of a new Chinese newspaper called Chung Pao (), which is managed by Fu Chaoshu (). The second part features a performance by Hong Kong singer Alan Tam () who holds solo concerts in Atlantic City, New Jersey. Tam and his girlfriend are interviewed by the host.
  - Video 305: CCTV, February 21, 1982; Cuid15070 (Box 100, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15070)
    This episode includes three parts: news reports, a program about Chinatown talents, and a cultural program. The first part covers international, local, and Chinatown news from the week. The news covers an anti-eviction campaign by Manhattan Lower East Side residents; a public hearing forum is held at La Salle Academy. The second part features two Chinese American accountants who use computers to assist taxpayers with filing tax returns. The third part features the Four Seas Players' drama play 72 Tenants () which is staged at Pace University in New York City.
  - Video 306: CCTV, February 28, 1982; Cuid15071 (Box 100, Videocassettes (u-matic) Cuid15071)